chadd_artaud@cox.net

GitHub: https://github.com/cartaud

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/chadd-artaud

EDUCATION

University of Nevada Reno

August 2016 – May 2020

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering - GPA 3.2

UC San Diego

Java Certification Program Full Stack Certification Program October 2021 – December 2021 March 2022 – Present

CAREER SUMMARY

Graduated with a Bachelor of Science degree in Mechanical Engineering from the University of Nevada Reno and successfully passed the Fundamentals of Engineering (FE) and Certified SolidWorks Associate (CSWA) exams. I have experience creating numerous full stack applications, both collaboratively and solo, where I showcase my knowledge in front and back end technologies.

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

• Object Oriented Programing

React

• Web APIs

• Express.js

Computer Science

Node.JS
 SQL

• Eagle Scout

HIGHLIGHTS OF PROJECTS

Projects:

- Tech Blog A CMS-style blog site similar to a Wordpress site, where developers can publish their blog posts and comment on other developers' posts as well.
- E-Commerce The back end for an e-commerce site with Express.js API to use Sequelize to interact with a MySQL database. The database contains tables for the categories, products and tags. All three tables are connected together using a product-tag table.
- Crime Watch A group project I collaborated on with three others that allows the user to search a city and return a map showing all recent crimes in that area. One of my roles for the project was to write the logic for retrieving the data returned from the crime API we used and filter the data to the map using custom icons for each crime.
- To view additional projects, please view my GitHub account @ https://github.com/cartaud

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Mechanical Engineering

Thermo Fisher Scientific – San Diego, CA

May 2019-August 2019

Mechanical Engineer Intern - Designed a neutron flux monitoring calibration system using SolidWorks and created
the software for it using LabView. Original system was obsolete so I collected a list of all required parts, made new
drawings of the chassis and backplane PCB using SolidWorks and selected updated hardware that met the required
specifications

Huntington Ingalls Industries - San Diego, CA

November 2020-Present

• Engineer I - Troubleshooting mechanical and electrical systems, writing detailed contracts, and supporting the navy. Wrote a program that reduces the amount of time by over half that our boat surveyors spend writing assessments on the boat. The program uses JavaScript and takes minimal input from the user to generates a full technical assessment of the boat being surveyed.